# **Hyeonmin Lee**

### in hyeonminlee1110 **𝚱** hyeonmin-lee.github.io/ ✓ frv9vh@virginia.edu

## Network Security Researcher (DNS/PKI/Internet Measurement)

I am a Postdoctoral Research Associate at the University of Virginia (UVA) with a Ph.D. in Computer Science, specializing in DNS security, PKI, and Internet measurement. With extensive publications in top-tier venues (e.g., USENIX Security, WWW, IMC), I have significant experience in designing and analyzing security protocols.

- Research Interests: Network security, with a focus on DNS, PKI/TLS, Email, and their measurement.
- Research and Project Experience: Led and participated in over ten research projects, collaborating with institutions such as Virginia Tech, Rochester Institute of Technology, University of Twente, SIDN Labs, and NLnet Labs, resulting in seven publications.
- Technical Expertise: Networking protocols (TCP/UDP/IP, DNS, HTTP/HTTPS, SMTP, etc), security protocols (DNSSEC, DoT/DoH, PKI, TLS, DANE, ECH, etc.), and Internet measurement (including the development of scanning tools and data analysis).
- Programming Tools: Python, C/C++, Java, Golang, Spark, Hadoop, Git, MySQL, ŁTĘX, Cloud platforms (AWS and Azure)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Postdoctoral Research Associate, Dept. of Computer Science

Oct 2023 — Present

University of Virginia

Charlottesville, VA, United States

- o [DNS-Web] Analyze the ecosystem of DNS HTTPS records, focusing on their deployment and management (Publication [C7]).
- o [TLS-PKI] Investigate the mutual TLS ecosystem, with emphasis on privacy leakage through certificates (Publication [C6]).
- o [Web-DANE] Analyze methods for adopting DANE in the web ecosystem by exploring obstacles.

Postdoctoral Researcher, Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering Seoul National University

Apr 2022 — Sep 2023

Seoul, South Korea

- o [TLS-DNS] Analyzed key material distribution in DNS to reduce TLS handshake time (Publication [C4]).
- o [DNS-DDoS] Developed a puzzle-based DDoS defense mechanism leveraging DNS for puzzle distribution (Publication [C5]).

Technical Research Personnel\*, Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering Seoul National University

Mar 2019 — Feb 2022

Seoul, South Korea

\*Technical Research Personnel is a form of military service (a combination of military service with a Ph.D. program) in which the service is fulfilled by carrying out research on technology. While fulfilling the service, I participated in or led several research projects; Please note that I had not been involved in any military-related projects.

o [DANE-Email] Investigated how the DANE protocol is deployed and managed in the SMTP ecosystem (Publications [C3, C2]).

Visiting Student, The Center for Cybersecurity

May 2019 — Aug 2019

Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY, United States

o [Email-DANE] Analyzed DANE to measure its deployment in the real-world (Publication [C2]).

Research Intern, Network Convergence and Security Lab

Aug 2015 — Feb 2016

Seoul National University

Seoul, South Korea

#### **EDUCATION**

**Ph.D., Computer Science and Engineering**, Seoul National University, (Seoul, South Korea)

Mar 2016 — Feb 2022

- o [Ph.D. Thesis] "Understanding the DANE Ecosystem in Email: How Is It Deployed and Managed?"
- o [Advisors] Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon (Seoul National University), Prof. Taejoong "Tijay" Chung (Virginia Tech)

B.S., Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, (Seoul, South Korea)

Mar 2011 — Feb 2016

Fall 2014

**Visiting Student, Information Technology**, *Uppsala University*, (Uppsala, Sweden)

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

[C7] Exploring the Ecosystem of DNS HTTPS Resource Records: An End-to-End Perspective (to appear)

IMC'24

Hongying Dong, Yizhe Zhang, Hyeonmin Lee, Shumon Huque, and Yixin Sun In Proceedings of the 2024 ACM on Internet Measurement Conference, Madrid, Spain, Nov 2024

[C6] Mutual TLS in Practice: A Deep Dive into Certificate Configurations and Privacy Issues (to appear)

IMC'24

Hongying Dong, Yizhe Zhang, Hyeonmin Lee, Kevin Du, Guancheng Tu, and Yixin Sun In Proceedings of the 2024 ACM on Internet Measurement Conference, Madrid, Spain, Nov 2024

[C5] DDD: A DNS-based DDoS Defense Scheme Using Puzzles

ICCCN'24

Hyeonmin Lee, Taehyun Kang, Sukhun Yang, Jinyong Jun, and Taekyoung Kwon In Proceedings of the 33rd International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks, Big Island, Hawaii, United States, Jul 2024

[C4] ZTLS: A DNS-based Approach to Zero Round Trip in TLS handshake

TheWebConf'23

Sangwon Lim, **Hyeonmin Lee**, Hyunsoo Kim, Hyunwoo Lee, and Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon *In Proceedings of the ACM Web Conference 2023 (formerly WWW)*, Austin, United States, Apr 2023

[C3] Under the Hood of DANE Mismanagement in SMTP

USENIX Security'22

**Hyeonmin Lee**, Md. Ishtiaq Ashiq, Moritz Müller, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, and Taejoong Chung *In Proceedings of the 31st USENIX Security Symposium*, Boston, United States, Aug 2022

[C2] A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email

**USENIX Security'20** 

**Hyeonmin Lee**, Aniketh Gireesh, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, and Taejoong Chung In Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium, Boston, United States, Aug 2020

[C1] Development of Cellular Core Network Enabling Network Function Virtualization

JCCI'18

Hyeonmin Lee, and Junghwan Song

The 28th Joint Conference on Communication and Information, Yeosu, Korea, May 2018

- [J1] TwinPeaks: An Approach for Certificateless Public Key Distribution for the Internet and Internet of Things *Computer Networks*Eunsang Cho, Jeongnyeo Kim, Minkyung Park, **Hyeonmin Lee**, Chorom Hamm, Soobin Park, Sungmin Sohn, Minhyeok Kang, and Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon *Elsevier Computer Networks* (SCI-E)
- [P1] A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email

**USENIX Security'22** 

**Hyeonmin Lee**, Md. Ishtiaq Ashiq, Moritz Müller, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, and Taejoong Chung *Poster Session in the 31st USENIX Security Symposium*, Boston, United States, Aug 2022

#### RESEARCH PROJECT EXPERIENCE (SELECTED)

## A Study for the Future-oriented DANE-based Web Architecture to Solve Problems in the Current TLS-based Web Ecosystem Primary Investigator Sep 2022 — Aug 2023

(Funded by Basic Science Research Program - National Research Foundation of Korea)

- o [Project Goal] This project aimed to study the impact of adopting the DANE protocol for peer authentication on the Web.
- o [Keywords] Web, Transport Layer Security (TLS), Authentication, DANE.
- o [Role] Analyzed the possibility of adopting DANE for the web by analyzing the issues in the current CA-based web ecosystem.

## Research on Secure DNS and Privacy aware Packet Filtering Technology

System Designer/ Programmer (Funded by Samsung Electronics)

Aug 2022 — Jul 2023

- [Project Goal] This project aimed to create a secure DNS environment for mobile devices by analyzing the performance of DNS over TLS (DoT) and DNS over HTTPS (DoH) and designing a DNS packet filtering mechanism.
- o [Keywords] Domain Name System (DNS), DNS over TLS (DoT), DNS over HTTPS (DoH), Packet filtering.
- o [Role] Designed a system that filters packets using DNS packets and implemented it based on BIND9.

#### Abnormal Detection and Forensic Techniques using IoT Network Traffic Analysis

## Project Manager/System Designer/Programmer

Mar 2021 — Nov 2021

(Funded by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC))

- [Project Goal] This project aimed to develop a system for detecting anomalies or attacks in IoT networks and generating evidence for digital forensics by collecting IoT network traffic.
- o [Keywords] IoT network, Network security, Machine learning, Abnormal detection, DDoS.
- [Role] Designed the entire system aimed at detecting anomalies in IoT networks.

#### **PATENTS**

- Method for Performing Mutual Authentication in Communication using Locator ID Separation Protocol, Apparatus, and System for Performing the Same (Registration No. 10-2476081, South Korea, Dec 2022)
  - Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon, **Hyeonmin Lee**, Hyunwoo Lee
- Network System and Method for Performing Message Security Thereof (Registration No. 10-2265611, South Korea, Jun 2021)
  - Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon, Hyunwoo Lee, Myungchul Kwak, Hyeonmin Lee, Junghwan Lim, Yoojung Shin
- Communication Method Based on Integrated Flat ID and System (Registration No. 10-2023115, South Korea, Sep 2019)
  - Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon, Hyunwoo Lee, Myungchul Kwak, Hyeonmin Lee, Dongjun Lee, Hyunchul Oh

#### **TALKS & PRESENTATIONS**

APNIC Blog, Online post, "Under the hood of DANE mismanagement in SMTP"

USENIX Security Symposium, Boston, "Under the Hood of DANE Mismanagement in SMTP"

Aug 2022

USENIX Security Symposium, Online, "A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email"

Aug 2020

## PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Reviewer: IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking (2024), IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management (2024)

External Reviewer: NDSS (2024)

## A Study for the Future-oriented DANE-based Web Architecture to Solve Problems in the Current TLS-based Web Ecosystem Primary Investigator Sep 2022 — Aug 2023

(Funded by Post-Doctoral Domestic and Overseas Training Program - National Research Foundation of Korea)

- [Project Goal] At present, the DANE protocol is mainly used for SMTP server authentication in mail transfers. This project aimed to investigate the impact of adopting the DANE protocol for peer authentication on the Web ecosystem.
- o [Role] Primary Investigator

### Research on Secure DNS and Privacy aware Packet Filtering Technology

Aug 2022 — Jul 2023

(Funded by Samsung Electronics)

- [Project Goal] This project aimed to design a secure DNS environment for mobile devices, which includes analyzing the performance of DoT/DoH in the mobile environment, designing a packet filtering mechanism based on DNS packets.
- o [Role] System Designer / Programmer

#### Research on Traceability for Data Stability on Cloud-edge Lifecycle

Apr 2020 — Dec 2021

- (Funded by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP))
- [Project Goal] This project aims to develop a technology that ensures the stability and traceability of cloud data by leveraging Trusted Execution Environment (TEE).
- [Role] Programmer

#### Abnormal Detection and Forensic Techniques using IoT Network Traffic Analysis

Mar 2021 — Nov 2021

- (Funded by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC))
- [Project Goal] This project aims to develop a system that detects anomalies (or attacks) in IoT networks and generates evidence for digital forensics by collecting IoT network traffic.
- o [Role] Project Manager (Lab.) / System Designer / Programmer

**Versatile Network System Architecture for Multi-dimensional Diversity** This project aims to design a network architecture that covers diverse network devices, services, or resources, especially, in the edge network.

Apr 2016 — Dec 2020 (Funded by *Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP)*)

- [Project Goal] This project aims to design a network architecture that covers diverse network devices, services, or resources, especially, in the edge network.
- o [Role] Project Manager (Lab.) / System Designer / Programmer

#### Research on GPU Acceleration for Fully Homomorphic Encryption

Feb 2020 — Nov 2020

(Funded by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC))

- [Project Goal] This project aims to accelerate Fully Homomorphic Encryption (FHE) techniques using GPUs, including research that reduces CPU-GPU interaction and CPU-to-GPU memory dependencies.
- o [Role] Programmer

#### Research on Distributed Web Structure and Counterplan

Aug 2019 — Nov 2019

(Funded by Korea Internet and Security Agency (KISA))

- [Project Goal] The project aims to analyze trends in the Distributed Web and draw a blueprint for applying it to the domestic web ecosystem.
- o [Role] Researcher

#### Research on Trust and Security Scheme for Interconnection of Heterogeneous Networks

Sep 2018 — Nov 2018

(Funded by Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI))

- [Project Goal] The purpose of this task is to analyze the authentication and networking methods of diverse IoT products and to propose a new framework to solve problems arising in heterogeneous network environments.
- o [Role] Researcher

#### Research and Development of Open 5G Reference Model

Aug 2016 — Feb 2019

(Funded by Giga KOREA Foundation)

- o [Project Goal] This project aims to develop an open-source 5G reference model and implement a simulator to test it.
- o [Role] System Designer / Programmer

#### Development of Network Security Acceleration for Next-generation Low-power SoC

Jul 2015 — Dec 2015

(Funded by Samsung Electronics)

- [Project Goal] This project aims to design a system that reduces the overhead of the TLS handshake by delegating the communication processes among low-power devices.
- [Role] Programmer